hello everyone my name is Greg and I Dev
stuff welcome everyone to episode 24 of
the tactics game in unity today we want
to expand our RPG system a little and
change it to be much more closer to
inspiration of the series Fire Emblem so
in the Fire Emblem you have attributes
which affects your stats
this line of variables consists of stats
and character information what we want
to introduce is attributes which will be
used to calculate the statistical
variables so let's make a public class
called character attribute
inside this character attributes we will
Define six attributes our game will have
I know we're lacking some of the Fire
Emblem attributes we might add them
later on in the development
let's make an empty Constructor because
we don't need to initiate anything in
this class
now in the character create a new
variable of type character attributes
called attributes
then create method called emit which
will be responsible for initializing the
character class
and inside to complete the
initialization we need to create new
instance of the character attributes
call init on start
to be able to see our attributes in the
inspector let's serialize by adding
attribute serializable
yeah that's confusing attribute
attribute C sharp attribute which
affects the class below him is inside
those square brackets it applies some
kind of effect to the class below him
good
so now what we want to do is to utilize
attributes to calculate values of the
character stats for example let's take
the damage right now it directly States
the current value of damage let's make a
method which returns damage which will
return damage which our character can
deal based on the type of the damage
this character deal
we can get the attribute responsible for
damage calculation for example for
physical we will take string and for
Magical damage we will take magic
attribute
so now if we select our character and
set the strength to for physical attack
to be 100 and magic for Magical attack
uh to be 100 we will do exactly 100
damage by both character
oh we have an issue is that on the start
we are arranged initializing the class
which nullify our attributes which we
set in the inspector so let's initialize
the class only if our attributes are
null meaning that there is no setting
set in the inspector we will do init on
start if the character attributes are
null
good
but our character are still using flat
armor value as their defensive stat
similarly we will create a new method
called get defensive Wireless
we need to pass the damage type so we
can identify what kind of damage our
character is receiving and calculate
Total Defense of the character based on
it
what we are doing right now is we are
isolating the calculation of the values
into the area which you can easily find
if later on you need to change
calculation of let's say half defensive
armor works you have exactly one place
to look for it
now let's use git defense value in the
attack method
we actually can get rid of the switch
statement
so we want to get the defense value from
the target based on the type of the
damage the character which attacks this
target is using
now let's set the skeleton due defense
high and launch the game
now if I attack this girl who have high
physical strength she will do little
damage well if I strike this girl who do
magic she will deal a lot of damage
bypassing physical resistance of the
skeleton dude
this episode brought to you by generous
support of people on patreon and members
on YouTube if you want to join them and
include my patreon in the description
and join button available right now on
YouTube
now let's expand our interface a little
let's add HP bar
this is not going to be a very pretty UI
additions but for now it will just serve
the purpose we will be expanding on UI
later on
duplicate the bar to make the exact copy
of the base for HP bar
recolor it
add the slider component to the HP Bar
base and set the HP bar to be its fill
object this component will be used to
use picture as a field amount of the bar
sliding like this
now inside the status panel script we
want to make HP bar show HP
make a serialized field for a slider for
HP bar
and in the update status set max value
of that slider and current value to be
player HP
if the editor reference the HP bar and
sets the HP bar slider setting to be
whole number
Let's test this
you will see how HP bar will change the
state but it only updates the state if
you move your mouse away for a moment
for now call update status in the update
this is not very optimal but we will
deal with this optimization later on in
the tutorial good as you can see it
works but the color is a little too
bright let's make it darker
good this is it for this episode if you
have any questions or any ideas about
code please leave your comment below if
you want to support me link in the
description
special thank you to the Salt garage
door David fahi for their generous
support with best regards see you in the
next episode